labondemand.com 2018-02-07

# LODS PRIVACY POLICY - Learn on Demand Systems

_June 9, 2017_

* * *

**1\. Collection of Your Personal Information**

We collect information as part of operating our Websites and services. In order to access the services of Learn on Demand Systems through this website, you may be asked to sign in with a Microsoft Account (formerly known as Windows Live ID), a Microsoft Corporate Active Directory Federation Services ID, or a Learn on Demand Systems’ ID. In such cases, and in order to provide you with our numerous services, we collect two types of information about our users: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-personally Identifiable Information. Our primary goal in collecting information from you is to provide you with a smooth, secure, efficient, and customized experience while using our site.

**Personally Identifiable Information:** This refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are. When you engage in certain activities on this site, such as registering for a membership, ordering a product or service, submitting content, filling out a survey, or sending us feedback, we may ask you to provide certain information about you by filling out and submitting an online form. It is completely optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, we may ask that you provide us personal information, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including zip/postal code), email address, employer, job title and department, telephone and facsimile numbers, and other personal identifying information. When ordering products or services on the site, you may be asked to provide a credit card number. Depending upon the activity, some of the information we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity.

**Non-personally Identifiable Information:** This refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. We may gather certain information about you based upon where you visit on our site in several ways, which information may be compiled and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis. This information may include the Website’s Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (“TCP/IP”) network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks like the Web use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web, allowing Web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet.

* * *

**2\. Collection Methods and Use of Information  **

We do not collect any Personally Identifiable Information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us. You provide certain Personally Identifiable Information to us when you: (a) register for our services and register your email address with us; (b) sign up for special offers from selected third parties; (c) send email messages, submit forms or transmit other information by telephone or letter; or (d) submit your credit card or other payment information when ordering and purchasing products and services on our site. We may also collect information from you at other points on our site that state that such information is being collected.

In addition, we may also collect, or our third-party content server may collect, certain Non-personally Identifiable Information. This information is ultimately stored in the form of store categories, and, in some cases, specific URLs. We use your IP address to diagnose problems with our servers and software, to administer our site and to gather demographic information.  Additionally, we use your IP address to determine your geo-location to help us optimize your user experience and to provide the best latency for your location.

We will primarily use your Personally Identifiable Information to provide our services to you, as required by our agreements with you. We will also use Personally Identifiable Information to enhance the operation of our site, fill orders, improve our marketing and promotional efforts, statistically analyze site use, improve our product and service offerings, and customize our site’s content, layout, and services. We may use Personally Identifiable Information to deliver information to you and to contact you regarding administrative notices. We may also use Personally Identifiable Information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our agreements with you, including our Site Terms of Use, Sales Terms and Conditions, and this Privacy Policy.

* * *

**3\. Release of Information  **

We do not sell, trade, or rent your Personally Identifiable Information to others. We do provide some of our services through contractual arrangements with affiliates, services providers, partners and other third parties. We and our service partners use your Personally Identifiable Information to operate our sites and to deliver our services.

We will encourage our service partners to adopt and post privacy policies. However, the use of your Personally Identifiable Information by our service partners is governed by the privacy policies of those service partners, and is not subject to our control.

Occasionally we may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personally Identifiable Information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

* * *

**4\. User Choices on Collection and Use of Information  **

We may, from time to time, send you email regarding our products and services. If you do not wish to receive emails you will have the option to opt out.

You also have choices with respect to cookies, as described below. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies some parts of our site may not work properly in your case.

* * *

**5\. Security of Information  **

At our site you can be assured that your Personally Identifiable Information is secure, consistent with current industry standards. The importance of security for all Personally Identifiable Information associated with our users is of utmost concern to us. Your Personally Identifiable Information is protected in several ways. Access by you to your Personally Identifiable Information is available through a password and unique customer ID selected by you. This password is encrypted. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. In addition, your Personally Identifiable Information resides on a secure server that only selected Learn on Demand Systems personnel and contractors have access to via password. We encrypt your Personally Identifiable Information and thereby prevent unauthorized parties from viewing such information when it is transmitted to us.

Personal information that you provide that is not Personally Identifiable Information also resides on a secure server and is only accessible via password. Since this information is not accessible from outside Learn on Demand Systems you will not be asked to select a password in order to view or modify such information.

In order to most efficiently serve you, credit card transactions and order fulfillment are handled by established third party banking, processing agents and distribution institutions. They receive the information needed to verify and authorize your credit card or other payment information and to process and ship your order.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this site cannot be guaranteed; and (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party.

* * *

**6\. Cookies  **

When you use our site we may store cookies on your computer in order to facilitate and customize your use of our site. A cookie is a small data text file, which a Web site stores on your computer’s hard drive (if your Web browser permits) that can later be retrieved to identify you to us. Our cookies store a randomly assigned user identification number necessary to keep you logged into our site.  The cookies make your use of the site easier, make the site run more smoothly and help us to maintain a secure site. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but some parts of our site may not work properly in that case.

We will not provide any third-party ad server with any of your Personally Identifiable Information. We may collect and use Non-personally Identifiable Information about you, such as your IP address, browser type, the server your computer is logged onto and the area code and zip code associated with your server.

* * *

**7\. Privacy Policies of Third Party Sites  **

Except as otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. Other sites accessible through our site have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. Please consult each site’s privacy policy. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. Additionally, other companies which place advertising on our site may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising through the use of cookies. We cannot control this collection of information. You should contact these advertisers directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

* * *

**8\. Miscellaneous Privacy Issues  **

You should also be aware that when Personally Identifiable Information is voluntarily disclosed (i.e. your name, email address, etc.) in any discussion forums or other public areas on this site, that information, along with any information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and used by third parties and may result in unsolicited messages from third parties. Such activities are beyond our control and this Policy does not apply to such information. Any submissions to chat rooms or other public areas on this site are accepted with the understanding that they are accessible to all third parties. If you do not want your comments to be viewed by third parties, you are advised not to make any submissions. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password and/or account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you’re online.

* * *

**9\. Changes to This Privacy Policy  **

We will occasionally update this privacy policy to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this Statement, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of this policy. If there are material changes to this policy or in how Learn on Demand Systems will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this policy to be informed of how Learn on Demand Systems is protecting your information.

* * *

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please [contact us and indicate “Privacy Policy” in the Comments field](http://www.learnondemandsystems.com/contact/).

* * *
